export default {
  id: 'jp_word_ms_noun_1_3_1',
  name: '일어달 명사 LV1-3 (100자 / 뜻)',
  data: [
    { question: '台', answer: ['だい', '~대 (기계, 수레를 세는 말) / ~대 (수량의 범위)'] },
    { question: '大事', answer: ['だいじ', '중대사, 큰일'] },
    { question: '退社', answer: ['たいしゃ', '퇴근'] },
    { question: '台所', answer: ['だいどころ', '부엌'] },
    { question: '台風', answer: ['たいふう', '태풍'] },
    { question: 'ただ', answer: ['', '무료'] },
    { question: 'ただいま', answer: ['', '지금, 방금'] },
    { question: '七夕', answer: ['たなばた', '칠석'] },
    { question: '食べ物', answer: ['たべもの', '음식'] },
    { question: '誰', answer: ['だれ', '누구'] },
    { question: '暖房', answer: ['だんぼう', '단방'] },
    { question: '近く', answer: ['ちかく', '근처'] },
    { question: '遅刻', answer: ['ちこく', '지각'] },
    { question: '地図', answer: ['ちず', '지도'] },
    { question: '駐車場', answer: ['ちゅうしゃじょう', '주차장'] },
    { question: '注文', answer: ['ちゅうもん', '주문'] },
    { question: '貯金', answer: ['ちょきん', '저금'] },
    { question: '一日', answer: ['ついたち', '1일'] },
    { question: '通学', answer: ['つうがく', '통학'] },
    { question: '月', answer: ['つき', '달'] },
    { question: 'つき合い', answer: ['つきあい', '교제함, 의리'] },
    { question: '都合', answer: ['つごう', '형편, 사정'] },
    { question: '妻', answer: ['つま', '아내'] },
    { question: '爪', answer: ['つめ', '손톱, 발톱'] },
    { question: '梅雨', answer: ['つゆ', '장마'] },
    { question: '手', answer: ['て', '손'] },
    { question: 'でき', answer: ['', '완성된 상태, 됨됨이'] },
    { question: 'デザイン', answer: ['', '디자인'] },
    { question: '天気', answer: ['てんき', '날씨, 쾌청한 날씨'] },
    { question: '電車', answer: ['でんしゃ', '전철'] },
    { question: '天井', answer: ['てんじょう', '천정'] },
    { question: 'てんぷら', answer: ['', '튀김'] },
    { question: '電話', answer: ['でんわ', '전화'] },
    { question: '床屋', answer: ['とこや', '이발소'] },
    { question: '所', answer: ['ところ', '장소'] },
    { question: '年', answer: ['とし', '나이'] },
    { question: '年上', answer: ['としうえ', '연상'] },
    { question: '図書館', answer: ['としょかん', '도서관'] },
    { question: '特急', answer: ['とっきゅう', '특급'] },
    { question: '隣', answer: ['となり', '옆'] },
    { question: '友だち', answer: ['ともだち', '친구'] },
    { question: '鳥', answer: ['とり', '새'] },
    { question: '取りたて', answer: ['とりたて', '갓 취득'] },
    { question: '努力', answer: ['どりょく', '노력'] },
    { question: '中', answer: ['なか', '속, 안'] },
    { question: '納豆', answer: ['なっとう', '낫토'] },
    { question: '涙', answer: ['なみだ', '눈물'] },
    { question: '何歳·何才', answer: ['なんさい', '몇 살'] },
    { question: '匂い', answer: ['におい', '냄새'] },
    { question: '肉', answer: ['にく', '고기'] },
    { question: '荷物', answer: ['にもつ', '짐'] },
    { question: 'ネクタイ', answer: ['', '넥타이'] },
    { question: '猫', answer: ['ねこ', '고양이'] },
    { question: '値段', answer: ['ねだん', '가격, 값'] },
    { question: '熱', answer: ['ねつ', '열'] },
    { question: '農産物', answer: ['のうさんぶつ', '농산물'] },
    { question: '喉', answer: ['のど', '목, 목구멍'] },
    { question: '飲物', answer: ['のみもの', '음료, 마실 것'] },
    { question: '飲み屋', answer: ['のみや', '술집'] },
    { question: '葉', answer: ['は', '나뭇잎'] },
    { question: '歯', answer: ['は', '이, 치아'] },
    { question: 'バーゲン', answer: ['', '염가 매출, Bargain Sale'] },
    { question: '灰色', answer: ['はいいろ', '회색'] },
    { question: '拝見', answer: ['はいけん', '삼가 봄 (みる의 겸양어)'] },
    { question: '拍手', answer: ['はくしゅ', '박수'] },
    { question: '箱', answer: ['はこ', '상자'] },
    { question: '初め', answer: ['はじめ', '처음'] },
    { question: '柱', answer: ['はしら', '기둥'] },
    { question: '二十歳', answer: ['はたち', '20세'] },
    { question: '鼻', answer: ['はな', '코'] },
    { question: '花', answer: ['はな', '꽃'] },
    { question: '花束', answer: ['はなたば', '꽃다발'] },
    { question: '花見', answer: ['はなみ', '꽃구경, 벚꽃놀이'] },
    { question: '母', answer: ['はは', '어머니'] },
    { question: '早起き', answer: ['はやおき', '일찍 일어남'] },
    { question: '早口', answer: ['はやくち', '말이 빠름'] },
    { question: 'バランス', answer: ['', '밸런스'] },
    { question: '春', answer: ['はる', '봄'] },
    { question: '番組', answer: ['ばんぐみ', '프로그램'] },
    { question: '反応', answer: ['はんのう', '반응'] },
    { question: '火', answer: ['ひ', '불'] },
    { question: '日', answer: ['ひ', '해, 날'] },
    { question: '日陰', answer: ['ひかげ', '그늘'] },
    { question: '光', answer: ['ひかり', '빛, 희망, 공명'] },
    { question: '髭', answer: ['ひげ', '수염'] },
    { question: '膝', answer: ['ひざ', '무릎'] },
    { question: '左', answer: ['ひだり', '왼쪽'] },
    { question: '人', answer: ['ひと', '사람, 타인'] },
    { question: '一休み', answer: ['ひとやすみ', '잠깐 쉼'] },
    { question: '火の車', answer: ['ひのくるま', '빈곤해 살림이 매우 쪼달림'] },
    { question: '病気', answer: ['びょうき', '질병, 나쁜 버릇'] },
    { question: '昼', answer: ['ひる', '낮, 점심'] },
    { question: 'ビル', answer: ['', '빌딩'] },
    { question: '服', answer: ['ふく', '옷'] },
    { question: '複雑', answer: ['ふくざつ', '복잡'] },
    { question: '不合格', answer: ['ふごうかく', '불합격'] },
    { question: '布団', answer: ['ふとん', '이부자리'] },
    { question: '船', answer: ['ふね', '배'] },
    { question: '踏み切り', answer: ['ふみきり', '건널목'] },
    { question: '風呂', answer: ['ふろ', '목욕'] }
  ]
}
